<chapter id="sum.introduction">
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <sect1 id="sum.introduction.scope">
        <title>Scope</title>
        <para>This document is the software user manual (SUM) for the IDEPIX processor.</para>
    </sect1>

    <sect1 id="sum.introduction.objectives">
        <title>Objectives</title>
        <para>
            IDEPIX is a BEAM scientific processor for multiple use. In the short term, it is serving as an experimental
            platform to evaluate the new products which are derived from the exploitation of the oxygen
            band. This work is done in the context and funded by the ESA O2 project. In parallel that part of the
            MERIS L2 processing which is relevant for the pixel classification is also implemented in IDEPIX.
            The objective is to test the standard MERIS pixel classification with the new pressure products.
            Furthermore, the pixel classification as developed in the GlobCover and AlbedoMap projects has been integrated
            in the IDEPIX processor. The objective is to compare the standard L2 pixel classification
            with the GlobCover one. This work is done for the MERIS Data Quality Working Group, and is
            funded through the “Pixel Classification Processor” workpackage of the BEAM maintenance contract.
            IDEPIX has grown from the former MEPIX processor and is currently being extended for the data
            processing of other instruments (such as AATSR and SPOT VGT) in the frame of various new
            projects (e.g. GlobAlbedo)
        </para>
    </sect1>

    <sect1 id="sum.introduction.readerLevel">
        <title>Reader Level</title>
		
		<para>
			This specification is mainly written for the following audiences:
			<itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
				<listitem>
					IDEPIX Application users
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>	
		</para>
		<para>
			The IDEPIX user manual specifications assumes that the reader is familiar with basic concepts in
			using the BEAM software and its integrated processors.
		</para>
        <para>
            NOTE: Since the processor is still under continuous development, this help manual may not always reflect
            the latest state.
		</para>
    </sect1>

    <sect1 id="sum.introduction.acronymsAndNomenclature">
        <title>Acronyms and Nomenclature</title>
        <sect2 id="sum.introduction.acronyms">
            <title>Acronyms</title>
			
			<para>
				<itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
					<listitem>
						BC - Brockmann Consult
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						ESA - European Space Agency
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						ESTEC -	European Space Technology and Research Centre
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						SUM - Software User Manual
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>	
			</para>
        </sect2>
        <sect2 id="sum.introduction.nomenclature">
            <title>Nomenclature</title>
        </sect2>
    </sect1>

    <sect1 id="sum.introduction.referenceDocuments">
        <title>Reference Documents</title>
		
		<para>
			<itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
				<listitem>
					[1] MERIS Level 2 Detailed Processing Model, PO-TN-MEL-GS-0006, 15 July 2009, Issue i8r0.
				</listitem>
                <listitem>
					[2] MERIS Level 2 Detailed Processing Model, PO-TN-MEL-GS-0006, 30 June 2005, Issue i7r3a.
				</listitem>
                <listitem>
					[3] Lindstrot, R., Preusker, R. and J. Fischer, 2008: The retrieval of land surface pressure from
                    MERIS measurements in the oxygen A-band. In preparation.
				</listitem>
                <listitem>
					[4] Lindstrot, R., Preusker, R. and J. Fischer, 2008: Empirical correction of stray light within
                    MERIS and the retrieval of surface and cloud-top pressure. Free University of Berlin,
                    Internal TechnicalNote.
				</listitem>
                <listitem>
					[5] R. Santer and O. Aznay, 2008: Direct to direct O2 transmittances: Determine the
                    surface pressure. LISE, Internal Technical Note.
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>	
		</para>
    </sect1>
</chapter>
