<chapter id="sum.processor">
    <title>IDEPIX Processor</title>

    <para>
        The IDEPIX processor user interface is represented by one main dialog, which
        curently consists of the following components:
        <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
            <listitem>
                 'I/O Parameters' Tab Pane
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                 'Cloudscreening' Tab Pane
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                 'IPF Compatible Products' Tab Pane
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                 'Pressure Products' Tab Pane
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                 'Cloud Products' Tab Pane
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                 'GlobAlbedo' Tab Pane
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                 'Run', 'Close' and 'Help' control buttons
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </para>

    <sect1 id="sum.processor.io">
        <title>I/O Parameters Tab Pane</title>

        <figure id="figure.processor.iotab">
			<title>I/O Parameters Tab Pane</title>
			<graphic scale="60" fileref="figures/iotab.png"/>
		</figure>

        This tab pane consists of the following components:
        <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
            <listitem>
                 Input product file: Select the input product file by either typing the product path into the text
                 filed or by pressing the file selection button to invoke a standard file dialog.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                Output product file: Select the output product file by either typing the product path into the text
                filed or by pressing the file selection button to invoke a standard file dialog.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                 Output product format and target directory:
                 <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
                    <listitem>
                        'Save as': If this checkbox is selected, the output product will be saved to disk.
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        Output product format: Select one of the available output product formats.
                    </listitem>
                    <listitem>
                        Select the output product directory by either typing the product path into the text
                        filed or by pressing the file selection button to invoke a standard file dialog.
                    </listitem>
                 </itemizedlist>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                'Open in Visat': If this checkbox is selected, the output product is opened in Visat
                after successful processing.
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </sect1>

    <sect1 id="sum.processor.cloudscreening">
        <title>'Cloudscreening' Tab Pane</title>
        The 'Cloudscreening' provides a list to select a cloud screening algorithm which is valid in the
        current context (instrument, project). In case an invalid algorithm is selected, the user
        will be notified. - This part is still under development.
    </sect1>

    <sect1 id="sum.processor.ipf">
        <title>'IPF Compatible Products' Tab Pane</title>

        <figure id="figure.processor.ipftab">
			<title>'IPF Compatible Products' Tab Pane</title>
			<graphic scale="60" fileref="figures/ipftab.png"/>
		</figure>

        This tab pane consists of the following components:
        <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
            <listitem>
                 'TOA Reflectances': If this checkbox is selected, the output product will contain
                  the TOA Reflectances (derived from radiance-to-reflectance conversion) for each MERIS band.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                 'Gas Absorption Corrected Reflectances': If this checkbox is selected, the output product will contain
                  the gas absorption corrected reflectances for each MERIS band.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                 'Land/Water reclassification flags': If this checkbox is selected, the output product will contain
                  an additional flag band derived from a land/water reclassification.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                 'Rayleigh Corrected Reflectances': If this checkbox is selected, the output product will contain
                  the Rayleigh corrected reflectances for each MERIS band.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                 'L2 Cloud Top Pressure and Surface Pressure': If this checkbox is selected, the output product will contain
                  bands with the L2 Cloud Top Pressure and Surface Pressure,
                derived as described in <xref linkend="sum.products.l2" xrefstyle="select: label"/>.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                'L2 Cloud Detection Flags': If this checkbox is selected, the output product will contain
                  a cloud classification flag band,
                derived as described in <xref linkend="sum.products.l2" xrefstyle="select: label"/>.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                'P1 Pressure Threshold': Text field to set the threshold for P1 pressure used for cloud detection.
                Default is 125 hPa.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                'PScatt Pressure Threshold': Text field to set the threshold for PScatt pressure used for cloud detection.
                Default is 700 hPa.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                'RhoTOA442 Threshold': Text field to set the threshold for RhoTOA at 442nm used for cloud detection.
                Default is 0.185.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                'User Defined Delta RhoTOA442 Threshold': Text field to set the threshold for the delta on the
                threshold of RhoTOA at 442nm used for cloud detection. Default is 0.03.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                'RhoTOA753 Threshold': Text field to set the threshold for for RhoTOA at 442nm used for cloud detection.
                Default is 0.1.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                'RhoTOA Ratio 753/775 Threshold': Text field to set the threshold for the RhoTOA ratio 753nm/775nm
                used for cloud detection. Default is 0.15.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                'MDSI Threshold': Text field to set the MDSI threshold used for cloud detection.
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        See [2] for details on the usage of these thresholds in MERIS cloud detection algorithm.
    </sect1>


    <sect1 id="sum.processor.pressure">
        <title>'Pressure Products' Tab Pane</title>

        <figure id="figure.processor.pressure">
			<title>'Pressure Products' Tab Pane</title>
			<graphic scale="60" fileref="figures/pressuretab.png"/>
		</figure>

        This tab pane consists of the following components:
        <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
            <listitem>
                 'Barometric Pressure': If this checkbox is selected, the output product will contain
                  a band with the barometric pressure derived for each pixel.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                 'Use GETASSE30 DEM for Barometric Pressure Computation':
                 If this checkbox is selected, the barometric pressure will be computed using
                the GETASSE30 DEM instead of the tie point DEM. Note that this option can only
                be used if the GETASSE30 DEM has been installed in BEAM.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                 'Surface Pressure (FUB, O2 Project)': If this checkbox is selected,
                  the output product will contain
                  a band with the surface pressure,
                  derived as described in <xref linkend="sum.products.o2.psurffub" xrefstyle="select: label"/>
                 for each pixel.
            </listitem>
             <listitem>
                 'Apply Tropical Atmosphere (instead of USS standard) in FUB algorithm':
                  If this checkbox is selected, a tropical atmosphere (instead of USS standard)
                  is used within the FUB surface pressure algorithm.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                 ''P1' (LISE, O2 project, all surfaces)': If this checkbox is selected,
                  the output product will contain
                  a band with the 'P1' pressure,
                  derived as described in <xref linkend="sum.products.o2.ptoalise" xrefstyle="select: label"/>
                 for each pixel over each surface.
            </listitem>
             <listitem>
                 'Surface pressure (LISE, O2 project, land)': If this checkbox is selected,
                  the output product will contain
                  a band with the surface pressure,
                  derived as described in <xref linkend="sum.products.o2.psurflise" xrefstyle="select: label"/>
                 for each pixel over land.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                 ''P2' (LISE, O2 project, ocean)': If this checkbox is selected,
                  the output product will contain
                  a band with the 'P2' pressure,
                  derived as described in <xref linkend="sum.products.o2.psurflise" xrefstyle="select: label"/>
                 for each pixel over ocean.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                 ''PScatt' (LISE, O2 project, ocean)': If this checkbox is selected,
                  the output product will contain
                  a band with the 'PScatt' pressure,
                  derived as described in <xref linkend="sum.products.o2.pscattlise" xrefstyle="select: label"/>
                 for each pixel over ocean.
            </listitem>
           
        </itemizedlist>
    </sect1>

    <sect1 id="sum.processor.pressure">
        <title>'Cloud Products' Tab Pane</title>
        The 'Cloud Products' provides options to write additional bands with GlobCover products.
        (<xref linkend="figure.processor.cloudqwg" xrefstyle="select: label"/>):

        <figure id="figure.processor.cloudqwg">
			<title>'Cloud Products' Tab Pane</title>
			<graphic scale="60" fileref="figures/cloudtab.png"/>
		</figure>

        This tab pane consists of the following components:
        <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
            <listitem>
                 'Blue Band Flags': If this checkbox is selected, the output product will contain
                  a band with 'Blue Band' flags derived for each pixel.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                 'Cloud Probability': If this checkbox is selected, the output product will contain
                  a band with cloud probability derived for each pixel.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                 'Combined Cloud Flags': If this checkbox is selected, the output product will contain
                  a band with 'Combined Cloud' flags derived for each pixel.
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        See section <xref linkend="sum.products.globcover" xrefstyle="select: label"/> for details on
        these GlobCover products.
    </sect1>

    <sect1 id="sum.processor.globalbedo">
        <title>'GlobAlbedo' Tab Pane</title>
        The 'GlobAlbedo' tab pane provides options to write additional bands produced with the
        GlobAlbedo cloud screening algorithm. This part is still under development.
    </sect1>
    

    <sect1 id="sum.processor.control">
        <title>Control Buttons</title>

        From all IDEPIX tab panes, the following control buttons can be accessed:
        <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
            <listitem>
                 'Run': If this button is clicked, the processor will start the computations.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                 'Close': If this button is clicked, the IDEPIX dialog is closed.
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                 'Help': If this button is clicked, this manual is displayed as online help.
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <figure id="figure.processor.controlbuttons">
			<title>IDEPIX control buttons</title>
			<graphic scale="60" fileref="figures/controlbuttons.png"/>
		</figure>

    </sect1>

    <sect1 id="sum.processor.gpt">
        <title>Processing from command line</title>

        Since the IDEPIX processor makes use of the BEAM graph processing framework, it can be
        used also as a command line tool outside BEAM-VISAT. The graph processing is invoked
        by the command
        <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
            <listitem>
                 ${BEAM-INSTALL-DIR}/bin/gpt
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        To obtain general help on the praph processing, use the command
        <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
            <listitem>
                 ${BEAM-INSTALL-DIR}/bin/gpt -h
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        Specific help on the IDEPIX processor, can be obtained with
        <itemizedlist mark='bullet'>
            <listitem>
                 ${BEAM-INSTALL-DIR}/bin/gpt -h idepix.ComputeChain
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        In this case, information on the usage and a list of all available parameters are given.
        <!--(see <xref linkend="figure.processor.gpt" xrefstyle="select: label"/>).-->


        <!--<figure id="figure.processor.gpt">-->
			<!--<title>IDEPIX command line processing</title>-->
			<!--<graphic scale="40" fileref="figures/mepix_gpt.png"/>-->
		<!--</figure>-->

    </sect1>

</chapter>
